umdearborn.edu 2019-06-15

# Privacy Policy

### Overview

The University of Michigan-Dearborn (UM-Dearborn) recognizes and values the privacy of the university community members and its guests, and strives to be the leaders and best in the ways in which we manage your personal information. This value is best reflected in Regent’s Bylaw Sec. 14.07. Privacy and Access to Information, which states in part:

“In collecting, utilizing, and releasing information about individuals associated with the university, the university will strive to protect individual privacy, to use information only for the purpose for which it was collected, and to inform individuals of the personal information about them that is being collected, used, or released."

Our privacy statement outlines the information we may collect, how we use it, how we protect it, and how you can elect to change your privacy settings related to the UM-Dearborn main website (umdearborn.edu) and activities related to UM-Dearborn Advertising and Marketing Information Collection.  

### Scope

This scope of this statement applies to our practices for gathering and disseminating information related to the UM-Dearborn main website (umdearborn.edu), and activities related to UM-Dearborn Advertising and Marketing Information Collection:

  * Our accountability
  * What information is collected
  * Why we collect this information
  * How this information is used
  * With whom will this information be shared
  * What choices you can make about this information
  * How is the information secured
  * Website Management
  * Privacy Statement Changes
  * Who to contact with questions or concerns

### Our accountability

At UM-Dearborn, we strive to appropriately manage, secure, and keep private and confidential the data entrusted to us.  

### What type of information do we collect

During a user visit to umdearborn.edu, the university automatically collects and stores certain information about the visit. Information collected includes:

  * The Internet domain from which a visitor accesses the website
  * The IP address assigned to the visitor’s computer
  * The type of browser the visitor is using
  * The date and time of visit
  * The address of the website from which the visitor has linked to umdearborn.edu

In addition, UM-Dearborn collects information from users that visit umdearborn.edu or through UM-Dearborn contracted for third-party advertising and marketing providers  (ex: Google Analytics, and Google Adwords). Information collected may include:

  * Content viewed during the visit
  * Date and time of visit
  * Amount of time spent on the website
  * Visitor location based on IP address
  * Demographic information

The UM-Dearborn website also may provide opportunities for site visitors to voluntarily provide personally identifiable information, such as their email address, name, telephone number or street address.  

### How this information is used

UM-Dearborn collects information about user visits that allows the university to monitor website performance, make improvements to site navigation and content, and better market to prospective students and other audiences.

The University may also collect personal information provided by site visitors for educational programs (ex: related to admission), administrative purposes (ex: related to employment), or university engagement (ex: attending a university sponsored event).  If you choose to share personally identifying information with us, that information will only be used for the purposes for which it was collected.  

### With whom will this information be shared

UM-Dearborn does not sell or rent your personal information. We may share your personal information in limited circumstances, such as with service providers that support business activities (ex: services that support student recruitment). We require our service providers to keep your personal information secure. We do not allow our service providers to use or share your personal information for any purpose other than providing services on our behalf. 

For information on our use of Google Analytics, please see the site “[How Google uses data when you use our partners' sites or apps](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).”

We may also share your personal information when required by law, or we believe sharing will help to protect the safety, property, or rights of the University, members of the University community, and University guests.  

### What choices you can make about your information

Users may opt out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting the [Google Advertising opt-out page](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en) or by installing the [Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

Visitors may also opt out of receiving third-party vendor cookies and messages by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative Consumer Opt Out website](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).  

### How is the information secured

UM-Dearborn recognizes the importance of maintaining the security of the information it collects and maintains, and endeavors to protect information from unauthorized access and damage. The University strives to ensure reasonable security measures are in place, including physical, administrative, and technical safeguards to protect your personal information.  

### Privacy Statement Changes

This privacy statement may be updated from time to time. We will post the date our Statement was last updated at the top of this Privacy Statement.  

### Who to contact with questions or concerns

Questions regarding this statement may be directed to the Office of External Relations at 313-593-5518 or through the External Relations website.
